# Carlo **Rosso**

#### Computer Science Student

ndanesinoo.github.io anesinoo carlo-rosso

#### About me

I began my Master's in Computer Science in September and am deeply passionate about the field. My enthusiasm was solidified during the internship, when I explored and understood the mechanics behind state-of-the-art machine learning algorithms. Currently, I am seeking a two-year student job position in the IT field.

### Professional Experience \_\_\_\_\_

Machine Learning Intern

Padua (PD), Italy 07/2024 - 08/2024

University of Padua

- · Studied the literature on sentiment analysis with SST-5 dataset.
- · Implemented and compared machine learning algorithms (Kernel Methods, RNN, LLMs)

Front Office Assistant

Padua (PD), Italy

University of Padua

08/2023 - 11/2023

· Data processing support, front office tasks, and archiving.

**Mechanical Worker** 

Motta di Livenza, Italy

TPA Srl

06/2019 - 07/2019

· Fabricated and assembled automated machines.

#### Education

#### **Master of Science in Computer Science**

University of Copenhagen

09/2024 - ongoing

· Interesting courses: Advanced Algorithms and Data Structures, Machine Learning, Integrative Structural Biology.

• GPA: 2.5

#### **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science**

University of Padua 09/2021 - 09/2024

Final Grade: 106/110.

• GPA: 3.5

**Exchange Student** 

Vejle, Denmark

Rødkilde Gymnasium

08/2019 - 05/2020

• The year of the COVID-19 pandemic.

# Projects \_\_\_\_\_

#### Somebody's Blog!

Anywhere in the world

Personal Project

ongoing

- Personal blog where I write my daily thoughts and experiences and todos.
- Technologies: Markdown, Rust, Workflow.
- Infrastructure to convert markdown into HTML.

#### **Easy Meal**

Software Engineer, University of Padua

- Web app to manage orders of restaurateurs.
- Group work of 6 students.
- · Backend: Node.js, Nest.js, Drizzle ORM and PostgreSQL.
- Frontend: **Angular**.
- · Developed and deployed in **Docker**.
- Evaluation: 25/30.

#### Music vs Robot

Object-Oriented Programming, University of Padua

- Tower-defense-style game.
- in C++14 with Qt framework.
- · Clear separation of concerns to enhance maintainability and scalability.
- Encapsulation, polymorphism, and modularity.
- Evaluation: 3/3 with honors.

## Spoken Languages \_\_\_\_\_

**Italian** Native

**English** Fluent, **IELTS 7.5**, Working on writing

Danish Work in progress, Basic

**Latin** Only reading, Love the poetry

Skills \_\_\_\_\_

Machine NLP, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Scikit-learn,

**Learning** Pandas, Numpy, HuggingFace

**Programming** 

Python, Haskell, Rust, Java, C++, C, Languages TypeScript, JavaScript, PHP, Golang, SQL,

Html, Typst, LaTex, Lua, Matlab

Computer Algorithms, Functional Programming, Science Git, Object-Oriented Programming, Data Structures, Database, Web Development

Interests \_\_\_\_\_

**Sports** Judo, **Sailing**, Skiing, Climbing

Hobbies Cooking, Open Source, Curiosity, Read-

ing, 3D Modeling, Music